<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Krux</title><link>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/</link><description>Recent content on Krux</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In Praise of Albums</title><link>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/albums/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/albums/</guid><description>I am in the lucky class of humans that have the liberty to listen to music with a bit more attention. That is because my work as a painter allows me to employ visual and auditory senses (and sense-making) at the same time. Not all artists are the same, but in my case the quality of my auditory input is more or less equivalent to the rate of my productivity and enjoyment at the easel.</description></item><item><title>RESILIENCE as Practice for Kingdom Dwellers (Part 1 of 5)</title><link>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/resilience/1-resilience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/resilience/1-resilience/</guid><description>The world is stitched together with RESILIENCE. Countless stories of resilience thread through the ages – a fundamental expression of our humanity. What is more, resilience shows up in many forms; it is not a single skill. Resilience is a complex embodiment of diverse competencies that enable people to thrive in difficulty. Some seem to be born with it, most have to develop their stores of resilience and grit.
Resilience asks the following questions: Are you able to persevere when things get difficult?</description></item><item><title>Live not by Lies (Nor by Fear)</title><link>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/2021-08-31_live-not-by-lies_jb-krohn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/2021-08-31_live-not-by-lies_jb-krohn/</guid><description>Drawn to Revelation It is not surprising to find oneself drawn to “the Revelation from Jesus Christ … to his servant John” (Rev 1:1) at a time such as this. To be sure, the Revelation is a strange book with bizarre creatures and indecipherable episodes re-imagined and re-purposed from an ancient vault of Biblical apocalyptic imagery. And, as GK Chesterton so aptly put it; “Though St. John the Evangelist saw many strange monsters in his vision, he saw no creatures so wild as one of his own commentators.</description></item><item><title>Tears – or, What are your Brutal Facts? Where lies your Deepest Faith? (Part 4 of 5)</title><link>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/resilience/4-tears/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/blog/resilience/4-tears/</guid><description>2 Corinthians 4:8,9 We are afflicted in every way, but not crushed; perplexed, but not despairing; persecuted, but not forsaken; struck down, but not destroyed; always carrying about in the body the dying of Jesus, that the life of Christ also may be manifested in our body.
Revelation 7:17 For the Lamb in the center of the throne will be their shepherd, and will guide them to springs of the water of life; and God will wipe every tear from their eyes.</description></item><item><title>JB Krohn</title><link>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/team/jb_krohn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/team/jb_krohn/</guid><description>Dr James Krohn is a theological educator, former pastor, and the founder-director of KRUX. He studied visual arts before moving on to focus on Theology; first studying under Dr JI Packer in Canada and later completing a DTh on Calvin’s Trinitarian vision in Stellenbosch. He has served on the faculties of the Bible Institute of South Africa and George Whitefield College, and as sessional lecturer at Regent College in Canada. James is married to Corli, and together with their five children they are avid outdoor enthusiasts and adventurers.</description></item><item><title>Otto Bam</title><link>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/team/otto_bam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andrewcloete.github.io/krux-web/team/otto_bam/</guid><description>Otto is a musician, writer, and lover of literature. With a master’s degree in English Studies and an established musical discography, he inhabits a world animated by story and layered with metaphor. Otto’s first full-length album, “The Fox and the Furrow” was released in 2015 under the stage alias Oddo Bam. With an overarching theme of pilgrimage, the album has a pensive undercurrent punctuated by rhythmic nuances and interjections of melodic guitar lines.</description></item></channel></rss>